let's get to the interview I've talked
long enough and some of you are probably
like wrap it up we want to hear what
John has to say so here's John kiraku
John like I said a dear friend a
colleague he was imprisoned uh he
exposed torture he spoke out against
Bush Administration torture said it was
water boarding he was prosecuted under
the Espionage Act under Obama
he was in prison for 30 months he got
out of prison he developed into a voice
against prison injustices a voice on the
Espionage Act through his experiences a
voice that stands in solidarity with
with with whistleblowers and a voice
that has been outspoken in support of
Assange and so uh listen to our
interview enjoy it there's a little bit
of a glitch video it looks like there's
some kind of glitch happening in The
Matrix but the audio is fairly clean and
I think you're going to appreciate our
conversation once again thank you for
tuning in to the unauthorized disclosure
podcast and I will be back next week
with r I hope but until then take care
of yourselves enjoy the
interview and uh it's really good to be
speaking with you and there's a lot to
get to but you know first let's yeah uh
toward the end of the show we'll get to
Julia Nan's appeal hearing that is
coming next week of course right now uh
activists press Freedom Advocates are
involved in counting down to what they
call day x because they believe that
this will be a San's last best hope uh
before the appeals court U but first we
had what was I think
maybe most one of the most significant
leak prosecutions under President Joe
Biden it took place or or the sentencing
for this case took place at the end of
January on January 29th it involved
Charles Little John he's an IRS
whistleblower and he's the one who
disclos the documents the tax returns
from Trump to the New York Times uh
so here's Charles Little John the IRS
whistleblower and this was him at
sentencing and so I'd like to ask you in
particular um as as somebody who went
through a leak prosecution about this
aspect of what happened because he got
an extraordinarily harsh sentence yeah
he did he got yes he did something close
to I believe uh I think he actually got
five years in
prison and uh so I'm just gonna read
this from you know from what I wrote up
and and just have you share your
reaction to all of this because I
thought that it was remarkable how the
prosecutors were so zealous in going
after him they basically said that uh
similar cases like his inadequately
accounted for the seriousness of
ideologically motivated leaks they
mentioned an IRS analyst named John Fry
who had leaked
to uh who had a who had been associated
with um leaking to prominent attorney
Michael Cohen um and then an employee of
the US Department of the treasur of
treasury's financial crimes enforcement
Network finsen Natalie Mayflower sour
Edwards you know she was someone who
released these finen files um for them
basically the government govern said
those cases were too short uh so you
should be more harsh that was the
request to the judge and
then looked to Espionage Act cases to
say to the court that you should
consider a recent case an employee of
the defense intelligence agency Henry
fzy was sentenced to 30 months in prison
after pleading guilty to communicating
top secret sensitive compartmented
information primarily over the telephone
to two reporters
um and I believe in there there might
have been a mention of reality winners
case and and other people who had much
longer
sentences so don't give him what you
normally would for leaking tax documents
to that that violated the privacy of
those taxpayers treat him like he
compromised National Security
information it's
outrageous there are so many things
wrong with this uh sentence first of all
the information was embraced by the
Biden campaign the Biden campaign used
uh the
information taken from the New York
Times which uh which Little John had
provided uh to to campaign against uh
Donald Trump the information was not
classified it was protected but it was
not classified and even if you don't
consider him to be a
whistleblower
um
the information the uh sorry this the
sentence was was so harsh as to put him
on par with what reality winner got in
her whistleblowing case which we all
complained was too
harsh it's like sentences have have gone
crazy in this country um already we're
known among industrialized countries for
the for the harshness of our of our
sentences on a Myriad of of crimes on
most crimes compared especially to our
Western European um allies but five
years for leaking unclassified tax
documents it's just stunning now one of
my complaints and I say this all the
time but I think it Bears repeating is
this is how these prosecutors get
promoted this is how they end up going
to the A-list uh law firms this is how
they end up uh uh basing their
Congressional campaigns their campaigns
for governor which they all eventually
want to do um in in my case for example
when it came to negotiating a
sentence uh there was there was one uh
assistant us attorney that was just
adamant adamant that I get uh uh five
years in prison I ended up with 23
months uh and what is she doing now
she's the deputy attorney general for
the Criminal
Division so this is how they make
reputations for for themselves it's how
they get promoted it's how they get
ahead in their careers their job is to
get you the longest possible sentence
now in this case I think we have to
blame the judge uh because there was as
you pointed out there was ample
precedent for a sentence of probation or
a sentence of uh what was it six
months and to go five years I'm sorry
there's just simply no justification for
something like that and are you familiar
with some of the absolute garbage that
was said by this judge I will just uh
I'll I'll bring this up here because
it's rather astounding so it was very
clear that the Biden justice department
was deciding that they wanted to send a
message to others we know especially
since President Barack Obama's
administration that many of these cases
are about making an example out of
individuals and it have to be because
there's so much leaking in Washington DC
and so the ones that do get prosecuted
are for a political
purpose this judge was saying
extraordinary things about little John
such as when you target the sitting
president of the United States you're
targeting the office and when you're
targeting the office Office of the
President of the United States you're
targeting democracy you're targeting our
constitutional system of
government and her her name is by the
way judge Anna Rees appointed by Biden
Rees also said the fact that he did what
he did and he's facing one felony count
I have no words for it and then when on
to say that the actions of
whistleblowing committed by little done
compared to the January 6th riots on
Capitol Hill your actions were also a
threat to our democracy and it engenders
the same fear that January 6 does it
cannot be open season on our elected
officials it just can't there was
nothing Noble or moral about the nature
of his offense you got a pretty good
tongue lashing from Leone brinka when
you were when you were sentenced for
your case but I don't knowes that sound
like it surpass what you had to sit
through before you were sentenced
officially uh yeah that surpasses what
judge Brink has said to me it's funny
that you bring that up because I was
actually gonna bring it up um judge
brinka said well first of all my my
attorneys had negotiated something
called an 11 c1c plea uh 11 c1c plea is
an agreement between the uh justice
department and the defense attorneys to
a guilty plea in exchange for a sentence
that is set in stone right and the judge
can't reject it or can't change it she
can reject it but she can't change it
judge brickma said that when she was
presented with this 11 c1c plea that she
had been a federal judge since
1986 and she had never seen an 11 c1c
plea and she said I don't like it I
don't like it one bit if I could give
you 10 years Mr kiraku I would give you
10 years well the truth is she could
give me 10 years all she had to do was
reject the 11 c1c but every National
Security journalist in Washington was in
the courtroom that day for my sentencing
and she was playing to the to the
reporters um with that said she never
accused me of weakening our democracy
she never accused me of domestic
terrorism so yeah this is worse and it's
also disingenuous you know I I don't
care if this was a a Biden appointee or
Trump appointee or from any other
president this judge made herself look
silly with a dumb statement like that
and as we made clear here this is tax
returns yes published by the New York
Times along with other tax files on Elon
Musk Jeff Bezos and
other very good tax Dodgers like they're
sophisticated they've been able to get
away with paying small amounts of money
to the IRS if you or I tried to do it we
would be audited or we would probably
find an IRS agent knocking on our door
yeah and uh yet she's equating the
publishing of this information or the
leaking of this information which is in
the public interest to rioting on
Capitol Hill like going through and
smashing windows and threatening to
string up Mike Pence or Nancy Pelosi
come on give us a break here
yeah this is really over the top you
know I I felt so sorry like you did I
felt so sorry when reality winter got
what was it five years and four months
it was just
outrageous um but to equate this with a
national security crime to equate the
release of tax information with with top
secret sensitive compartmented
information it's just a it's it it
doesn't make any sense to me at all
unless maybe it's in the National
Security interests of the US to protect
the 1% from having us you know see how
much they don't pay when they're
expected to pay their taxes that's right
uh and so okay that brings us to the
elites of this country uh and before we
move on to other cases that are all
basically all in one universe so I'm
putting them off for the end of our
conversation let's get to that
bizarre report from the special Council
about Joe Biden President Joe Biden's
mishandling of classified documents
because this to me was a rather wacky
document that got thrown out there for
everyone uh and so here's this is the
box or one of the boxes that was circled
it's in this garage it said that there's
classified Afghanistan documents that
the FBI found in 22 when they went and
searched his home in
Delaware and in particular I want to I
want to raise this uh
because you
know you went through your own
prosecution so I I imagine that you read
a document like this it might make you
feel a little bit
infuriated because you sat through
lectures about how classified
information has to be protected and they
made it seem like it was essential that
these kinds of criminal prosecutions
take place and right you prosecutor
could never show discretion so what I
have up on your here on the screen is I
actually have these inverted this isn't
exactly the order in the document but
I'll read it like this the practice of
retaining classified material in
unsecured locations and re and and
reading classified material to one's
Ghost Rider present serious risks to
National Security
give them the vulnerability of
extraordinarily sensitive information to
loss or compromise to America's
adversaries the department routinely
highlights such risks when pursuing
classified mishandling prosecutions but
addressing those risks through criminal
charges the only means available to this
office is not the proper remedy here in
reaching our decision we did not
consider every circumstance in which
criminal charges against a former
president or vice president for
mishandling classified information may
be warranted but on the facts of the
case and this is from the Department of
Justice principles on there I never knew
that this was a language that was on the
justice department site but apparently
they use this phrase the facts of this
case the fundamental interests of
society the fundamental interests of
society do not require criminal charges
against Mr Biden and for this additional
reason yada yada yada we're declining
prosecution
so so yeah there it is it's not in the
fundamental interests of society to
prosecute Joe
Biden you know I wrote an oped uh in
consor news I'm gonna say it's almost
two years ago now whenever whenever
Donald Trump was initially um caught
with the classified documents at maral
Lago and uh the oped was head LED don't
charge Donald Trump with Espionage and
the sub headline was and don't charge
anyone else either uh we need to come up
with
something akin to what we had in the
1990s when classified information was
mishandled or allegedly mishandled and
I'll I'll recount a story that I've told
you in the
past at the CIA in the 199 I sat next to
a woman who was having an affair with a
man who used to be a senior Cia officer
he had retired and he had gone to CNN as
a uh terrorism
consultant and in the course of pillow
talk she relayed classified information
to him he went on CNN and repeated the
classified information the CIA began an
investigation they
immediately tied it right back to
her she was not charged with Espionage
what they did was they wrote a strongly
worded letter and put it in her
personnel file they suspended her
without pay for two weeks and she was
ineligible for a promotion for a period
of one year that's how you handle the
misuse of classified information now you
saw the picture you you just posted the
picture of the Box in Joe Biden's garage
who had access to that information who
who saw the information who was the
information revealed to nobody maybe it
went to his Ghost Writer okay shame on
you you should have a strongly worded
letter put in your personnel file but
Espionage sorry same with Donald Trump
Donald Trump has a problem he has lots
of problems but in this case he had a
problem with with taking classified
information
uh with him in his
retirement did he publish it did he turn
it over to Fox News is society a more
dangerous place because of it no not
that anybody has proven and so you know
let's put a strongly worded letter in
his personnel file or something but to
charge him with
Espionage which in some cases can be a
death penalty case no I'm sorry it's not
appropriate we need to revamp the whole
thing you and I have talked about this
at length both privately and uh and you
know on your podcast and on my radio
show the the Espionage Act needs to be
scrapped and Rewritten so that it
targets people who mean harm to our
country people who are working on behalf
of foreign governments or foreign
entities or dangerous terrorist groups
or something like that not for some
absent-minded politician who leaves
boxes in his garage
sorry you're absolutely right before the
people like you and other whistleblowers
and other lower level leakers who had
their lives destroyed or people who were
found to be retaining documents in their
homes and had their homes rated by the
FBI I would just like to before we move
on from Joe Biden read this part from
the special council's report and I just
read this
to bluntly call out the special counsel
and his team for printing in
this
because I have followed justice
department
prosecutions and this is not how others
have been prosecuted so I just want to
read this it
says so let me
backtrack we didn't say this so to make
sure that everyone listening understands
what Biden was found to
have in his possession or found to have
done he had these documents he
apparently took these records that
showed that he opposed the troop surge
that President Obama wanted for
Afghanistan admirable glad he opposed it
then he uh had these notebooks and he
shared them with his Ghost Rider and
there are recordings of Joe Biden
speaking to his ghost writer and
apparently leaking classified
information from these notebooks that
had highly sensitive military National
Security other things that had been
noted from I think presidential daily
briefings of meetings of that nature so
this is what the special Council wrote
for an oral disclosure of information as
opposed to the disclosure of a
classified document the government must
prove that the possessor has reason to
believe the information could be used to
the injury of the United States or to
the advantage of any foreign Nation
accordingly to establish that Mr Biden
violated section 793 e that's in the
Espionage Act when he read the
information from his notebooks to his
ghost riter we would need to prove that
he acted with an intent to violate the
law and had reason to believe the
information he disclosed could be used
to harm the United States or benefit a
foreign
Nation um
so like that's not how people are
prosecuted no it's not it's not and you
know you know as well as I do Kevin I'm
sorry to interrupt you but in in my case
a precedent was set when judge Len
brinka said that she would not respect
the precedent that had been set in the
Tom Drake case that that the the
defendant had to have Criminal Intent to
leak the document she said Mr kiraku you
either did it or you didn't do it it and
I think you did it and my attorney stood
up and said your honor are you saying
that a person can accidentally commit
spage and she said that is exactly what
I'm
saying right so this whole thing of
intent to violate the
law when you talk to your ghost riter
you were violating the law and your
intent to share that information with
your ghost riter is your V like that is
the intent like but also to me that also
seems to be a very Twisted way of of of
viewing laws it's like I didn't mean to
kill that person therefore I should not
be punished for killing that person
because I wasn't really trying to murder
them that doesn't sound like how people
get off and get away with crimes in this
country or or just just don't go to pray
I mean basically he's saying since Biden
didn't intend to violate the Espionage
Act he can't be prosecuted for violating
the Espionage Act but that and then it's
saying that if he then it says had
reason to believe the information he
disclosed could be used to harm the
United States or benefit a foreign
Nation but again the reason to believe
the information would do such a thing it
comes from all the meetings you have
with people in government that advise
you about the sensitivity of that
information correct like that's that's
how you are on notice that you have to
protect the information and not leak it
absolutely and then when you're when
you're first given a security clearance
you have to sign secrecy agreements
saying that you'll never disclose the
information that you uh come across and
then every time you're read into a a
compartment which which makes up
sensitive compartmented information
special compartmented information you
sign new secrecy agreements saying that
you're never going to disclose the
information um and we all know that that
the
um that the uh president's Daily Brief
is the most highly
classified publication that comes out of
the intelligence
Community you can't disclose that stuff
yeah and David Petraeus I think did
something almost similar to Joe Biden
Joe Biden wasn't having an affair with
his ghost riter but Joe but but David
Petraeus shared these notebooks they
called them black books in PR yeah and
his biographer Paula Broadwell had
access to all of these and was
referencing them for his the the the
faing biography that was written about
him so anyways let's move on to the next
thing which is to discuss what happened
to Joshua schy the sentencing he
received uh it was over 40 years or it
was about for I think it was 40 years 40
years yep 40 years sentence uh now up
top uh it's treated separately so let's
treat it separately there were two
different trials yes we know that he was
accused of having child sexual assault
material on his computer and he was
convicted of it and he received six to
seven years in prison for it and that's
serious violation and whatever was
happening with that material it looks
ugly that being said that's not our
concern that's not what you and I deal
with so I'm just going to set that aside
the same way the court set it aside
because if you look at what the
prosecution was
doing they reserved their worst and most
aggressive
prosecution for the leaking that Joshua
Schult he did he got
33 and a half years I think for the
disclosure of these materials and in
particular I want to draw your attention
and get your response to the fact that a
terrorism enhancement was added to one
of the charges what do you think about
that the the computer crime offense was
apparently on on a list was it added to
a list after the Patriot Act was adopted
following the September 11th attacks and
so being on this list the government
went in there and decided they were
going to ask for this terrorism
enhancement and they said that they
needed to do this because of the fact
that he had uh he had tried to retaliate
he had a calc sorry
he his offense was calculated to
influence or affect the conduct of
government
intimidation or coercion or to retaliate
against government conduct so in
particular he was retaliating against
government conduct by releasing the CIA
hacking materials to WikiLeaks so a leak
even though we're talking about a
computer crime
offense basically if they could have
they would have tried to do this to the
Espionage Act and made it a terrorism
offense they're going after him and
saying basically that leaking to
WikiLeaks was tantamount to terrorism
terrorism there are so many things wrong
uh with his sentencing um we should we
should give a little bit of background
here
too this was the second time that he was
tried for these alleged crimes the first
time he was he was acquitted of two
charges and the jury hung on all the
other
charges and then Josh schy did something
very very
stupid he fired his attorneys and
elected to represent
himself and um by all accounts uh he
came across to the jury as as
arrogant uh which didn't do him any
favors now one of the things that I
think was a real disservice to him was
was the fact that um there was no
evidence there was no documentary
evidence that he had ever downloaded
anything from the CIA system and passed
it to WikiLeaks and what the justice
department said to explain that was that
he was such a genius such a computer
genius that he was able to completely
cover his
tracks and the reason
why he's
guilty is that there is no evidence
against
him that doesn't make any sense at
all but apparently there were a lot of
noding heads in the uh in the jury box
and so he rejects this label of
whistleblower he says that he never sent
Wikileaks anything okay fine I call him
a whistleblower you call him a
whistleblower
um I also want to say something about
enhancements first of all this terrorism
enhancement is just outrageous and
there's no recourse you can't appeal an
enhancement it's just it's just up to
the judge at the request of the
prosecution but what is an enhancement
if you go to the Justice Department's
website and you look at the sentencing
schedule it looks like an Actuarial
chart right this is I would really
encourage everybody to do this
so you have on the leftand side you have
levels 1 through
40 with one being you you know jaywalked
on federal property right and across the
top from from left to right there are
something like seven columns number
column number one is you've never been
in trouble in your life number seven is
your career criminal you commit federal
crimes every single day and the others
are in between so level
Seven is the federal death penalty right
that's the the most serious level you
can be and then the other extreme is you
know they don't even waste their time
Prosecuting you okay
so Josh schy had never been in trouble
in his life
so they charge him with Espionage which
is actually level 27 on on a a scale of
1 to
40 so level 27 calls for something like
nine years in
prison how did he get
40 well they gave him an enhancement for
terrorism they gave him an enhancement
for hacking they gave him an enhancement
for this is one of my favorite ones
failure to take
responsibility so if you are charged
with a crime you plead not guilty you go
to trial and you're found guilty they
saywell you were lying when you said you
were not guilty so that means you failed
to take responsibility for your criminal
Behavior that's an enhancement so
instead of being a level
27 the first enhancement makes it a 29
the second a 31 the third a 33 all of a
sudden that nine years becomes 40 years
that's how they did it and we should
also mention that he was kept in
horrendous conditions oh I just wrote
about this the special administrative
measures which I imagine to some of some
degree will carry over to wherever he's
going to be incarcerated I know correct
that the judge said to keep him
reasonably close to somewhere in the
central part of the United States I I
don't I don't actually know off the top
of my head where he's from
but they wanted to move him closer to
his family it's usually good luck with
that yeah well I mean How likely is it
that he gets put in like Florence
Colorado you know the the
super yeah Florence Maran or terot mark
my words those are CM so the
communication management units yeah
correct um listen the judge recommending
to the justice department that they keep
him close to family is like me
recommending to the justice department
that they keep him close to family it
counts for literally nothing because is
is it is the sole it is the sole
responsibility of the Bureau of Prisons
to decide who goes where the judge can
say all he or she wants that as my judge
did that I should go to a minimum
security Work Camp it makes no
difference to anybody and and this holds
with Julian Assange as well we can talk
about that whenever you want but for
well so
just just leading into Assange I was
going to mention that the terrorism
enhancement is certainly something that
I would expect
his attorneys in people who are
advocates for him to now raised in the
context of these extradition proceedings
yes because we're talking about the
potential for cruel and inhuman
treatment and this computer crime
offense is there's there's very few
people who have been prosecuted under
the Espionage Act who have also had this
charge affixed to them which may be kind
of stunning you know you you think the
justice department is very aggressive so
probably there are a lot of these cases
but it's not always that people who have
done these leaks have also faced
computer crime offenses even though they
could because mind you all of this
information is being downloaded from
computers that's right so I'm not quite
sure what's going on at the justice
department in their National Security
division reality winner didn't have it
Daniel hail did not have it Terry Albury
did not have it and I think there's one
more recent case that I thought it was
remarkable that they didn't get it but
Julian Assange does and Chelsea Manning
did and Chelsea Manning didn't get a
terrorism enhancement however the
military went after her and said that
she had aided the enemy you might recall
I do and and splashed around this
evidence that made it seemed like she
had helped Al-Qaeda indirectly by
leaking to WikiLeaks and so I fear that
this is going to come back to Julian
Assange I fear that through this
conspiracy to commit a computer crime
that juliia Assange is going to
be this won't be in the UK because they
want to be careful but in a US trial in
that setting I fear that the US
government is going to have its knife
out and ready and will say that Julia
Assange aided
terrorists I think that's exactly what's
going to happen they tried the same
thing with Tom Drake you'll recall what
15 16 years ago now um in fact Tom tells
a really wonderful story um about a prer
meeting that he and his attorneys had
with the the prosecutors at the justice
department and one of the prosecutors
said um you have the blood of American
soldiers on your hands and he said who
blood what soldier name one name one
single soldier and everybody just went
silent they try this kind of garbage all
the time saying that people have died
because of your Revelations there's
blood on your hands uh that that you've
given Aid to uh Aid and comfort to the
enemy and and to terrorist groups none
of it's none of it's true you you recall
probably better than anybody that after
uh the the Chelsea Manning case was
completed the head of NSA at the time
came out and said that there was no
discernable harm to the National
Security none zero it was
embarrassing to see what people say
behind closed doors but there was no
harm to the National
Security just like with uh this this IRS
guy little John there's no harm to the
National Security they can compare his
case to as many DEA or Dia cases as they
want there's no harm and just like with
Julian Assange
there's no
harm yeah exactly and so we've got this
hearing coming up uh but on my way to
getting your final thoughts for this
episode and letting you give some
parting words about juliaan Assange and
the fact that we have this major hearing
I do want to mention that we have news
uh that I haven't had a chance to write
up yet talking to you but I'm going to
get something together because I've been
closely following this case the CIA is
going to invoke the state Secrets
privilege in this lawsuit that I thought
was rather incredible because the judge
did not dismiss it and allowed a a
a basically complaint against the CIA to
stand that they could go and
litigate and it involves well I'll let
the CIA tell you because here's what I
have from the memo they just submitted
to the court after the Court's recent
decision on the government's motion to
dismiss the sole remaining claim in this
case is the plaintiff's allegation that
at the cia's request the Spanish
defendants we're talking about UC Global
this private security company that
targeted Assange that they illegally
downloaded the contents of the
plaintiff's electronic devices when they
visited Julian Assange at the Ecuadorian
Embassy in London and transmitted these
materials to the CIA so these are two
journalists and two attorneys that have
sued said their privacy rights were
violated the CIA continues any factual
inquiry into these allegations whether
they are true or not would implicate
classified information as it would
require the CIA to reveal what
intelligence gathering activities it did
or did not engage in among other things
because the CIA cannot publicly reveal
the very facts over which it is seeking
authorization the very facts over which
it is seeking authorization to assert
the State Secrets privilege that
sentence is written weird anyways they
um are going to invoke the state
Secret's privilege to prevent a judge
from holding them accountable for
copying people's
Electronics I've been talking to um UBS
whistleblower Brad berkenfeld about this
at length over the last uh week or so
Brad visited Julian on two occasions in
the Ecuadorian Embassy in London and
Brad of course is an American citizen
born and raised in the United States uh
he turned his cell phone in uh just like
every visitor to the Ecuadorian Embassy
did and now is confident that his
information was illegally improperly
downloaded by uh this Spanish contractor
and turned over to the
CIA and there's no recourse this is
clearly obviously a legal constitutional
violation and uh there's nothing that uh
anybody can do uh about it you know
there is a deep State and you can call
it whatever you want you can call it the
Deep State you can call it the state you
can call it the federal bureaucracy
whatever it is it tramples the
constitutional rights of uh of average
American citizens and there is no
recourse this is yet another example
yeah they're doing it right now because
as we record this podcast they're saying
to the Congress you're going to go in a
close session and debate 702
reauthorization for uh surveillance
authorities for the NSA we don't want
this to happen out in the in the open
for for the public to respond and and
tell us that we need to change how we do
all of this John Cod the judge he can
accept this or he cannot he actually
could say that you're not allowed to
invoke the state Secrets privilege but
you know what there's very very few
judges that would do he might he might
but I hear he's retiring soon he's he's
a much older judge and
so if he didn't grant them the state
Secrets privilege I fear that the CIA
just drags this out and then hopes that
the case gets reassigned and then tries
to find a way to invoke the state
Secrets privilege again later on down
the road there's always I mean there are
Masters at procedurally gaming the syst
absolutely absolutely they are and this
really makes me fear for the civil
liberties of of all Americans because it
looks like they're going to get away
with this and if they get away with it
now they're going to get away with it
next time because a precedent will have
been set or reset and then you know
where do we turn from there where do we
go all right so I'll let you have the
last words here anything you want to say
about the pivotal hearing that is
happening on February 20th and what's at
stake and how I think people should
understand this is the first chance for
Julian Assange and his legal team to go
before this court and say that that
lower court decision The District Court
decision from 2021 must be reconsidered
because it was not acknowledged and
recognized that juliia Assange has press
Freedom rights that's right um I've
spoken to a lot of people about this
hearing next week Julian's uh relatives
uh his UK attorneys one of his American
attorneys even people at Wikileaks and
everybody is pretty certain that he's
going to be not just extradited a week
from tomorrow but but whisked directly
from the courtroom to a waiting FBI
plane and flown immediately back to the
United States if and when that happens
it's up to all the rest of us to stand
up we're going to have
to maintain a presence at that
Courthouse we have to go to Every
hearing we have to stand outside we have
to talk to the media we have to March we
have to write we have to to meet with
citizens who need to be educated on this
uh on this
issue uh because there's a very thin
line between Julian and all the rest of
us Julian is obviously a publisher he's
obviously a journalist and any
conviction any
prosecution would put every National
Security journalist in America on the
firing line I mean the Constitution
really is what is at stake here and so
if the government is going to try to
chip away the Constitution it's up to
the rest of us to fight them on it we we
have to we we can't go down without a
fight we we owe it to ourselves if not
to
Julian well thank you John it was really
great to be able to speak with you I'm
glad I was able to talk with you about
all of these stories and these important
issues and everyone should go read uh
your articles you have a substack and uh
you're also regularly contributing to
Consortium news so thank you very
much